# VIKRANT **SINGH**

+91-8968352525



vsc.uiet@gmail.com



vikrantsingh.tech



# **SUMMARY**

Dedicated Flutter Developer with 2 years of experience specialising in creating cross-platform mobile applications. Proficient in Flutter framework, Dart programming language, and building responsive UI designs. Experienced in integrating third-party APIs and optimising app performance for both iOS and Android platforms.

# **EDUCATION**

## **UIET, Panjab University**

Software Engineer 2

B.E (Computer Science and Engineering) 2018 – 2022

#### SKILLS

- Strong knowledge of the flutter framework and the dart programming language.
- Strong understanding of Bloc, Provider and Riverpod state management in flutter.
- Knowledge of design patterns (e.g., MVC, MVVM)
- Great understanding of RESTful APIs.
- Familiarity with Firebase integration for authentication, push notifications, crashlytics, cloud functions etc.
- Familiarity with CI/CD tools for continuous integration and deployment. (e.g., Codemagic, Github Actions)
- Familiarity with Agile methodologies.
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously

# **PROFILES**

- Github: vsc9729
- Hackerrank: vsc\_uiet
- Linkedin: vikrant-singh-2146ba1a1
- Youtube: <u>flutter gems</u>

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Software Engineer 2**

GeekyAnts Pvt. Ltd. | September 2023 - Present

- Spearheaded the development of <u>Tata MD</u> for The Tata Group in India, from project inception to delivery.
- Designed and implemented all core modules of the application, showcasing expertise in mobile app development and Flutter framework.
- Facilitated seamless communication between the development team and Tata's backend team, effectively addressing bugs and incorporating enhancements for optimal app performance and user experience.

#### **Software Engineer 1**

GeekyAnts Pvt. Ltd. | September 2022 - September 2023

- Contributed significantly to the development of multiple Flutter-based application, gaining expertise in BLoC state management and GraphQL, while actively participating in decision-making processes.
- Worked with native code while integrating external modules(e.g. Banuba video sdk).
- Demonstrated leadership skills by taking on a lead role in the projects, overseeing their successful execution and contributing valuable insights to drive project advancements.

### **Software Engineer Intern**

GeekyAnts Pvt. Ltd. | June 2022 - September 2022

- Acquired foundational skills in web development, including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, and MongoDB during the first month of the internship period. Demonstrated proficiency by working on various web development concepts and projects.
- Specialised in advanced Flutter concepts over the following 2 months, contributing to the development of some internal applications with a GraphQL backend. Successfully applied the learned skills to create a functional demo project showcasing expertise in mobile app development.